老兄  真奇怪
Man, this is weird.
你发现了吗  脆脆上尉的眉毛长在帽子上
You ever realize Captain Crunch's eyebrows are actually on his hat?
那就叫奇怪了
That's what's weird?
乔伊  他已经当了四十年早餐片的上尉
Joey, the man's been captain of a cereal for the last 40 years.
怎样
What?
汤匙  你舔完放回去
The spoon! You licked and you put.
你舔完放回去
You licked and you put.
是啊  怎么了
Yeah, so?
你不知道有多恶心吗
Don't you see how gross that is?
就像你用我的牙刷一样
I mean that's like you using my toothbrush.
你用了我的牙刷
You used my toothbrush?
那是因为我用红的那支去通排水孔了
Well, that was only 'cause I used the red one to unclog the drain.
红色是我的
Mine is the red one!
真是一发就不可收拾了
Oh, God! Can open. Worms everywhere!
为什么牙刷不能共用
Why can't we use the same toothbrush...
肥皂就可以共用
... but we can use the same soap?
因为肥皂是肥皂  它会自我清洁
Because soap is soap. It's self-cleaning.
好吧  下一次你洗澡的时候
Alright, well next time you take a shower,
想想我什么最后洗  跟你什么最先洗
...think about the last thing I wash and the first thing you wash.
瞧这两个小帅哥
Look at you fancy lads!
有什么大事
What's the occasion?
知道我节目里那个演昏迷不醒的人吗
You know that guy on my show that's in a coma?
他要请我吃饭
He's having a brunch.
-就等你了  -好的
- Ready when you are. - Okey-doke.
真不敢相信  你们真的要去纹身了
I can't believe you're actually getting tattoos.
什么  你们要去纹身
Excuse me, you guys are getting tattoos?
对  不能告诉罗斯  我要给他一个惊喜
Yes, but you can not tell Ross 'cause I want to surprise him.
真不错  你们要纹什么
Wow, this is wild! What are you gonna get?
我要纹一朵百合
I'm getting a lily.
为了纪念我妈  她就叫百合
For my mom, because her name's Lily.
真幸运  她要是叫大污点怎么办
That's lucky. What if her name was Big Ugly Splotch?
-那你们要纹哪里  -在肩上吧
- So where you gettin' it? - I think on my shoulder.
什么
What?
什么在你肩上
What's on your shoulder?
裂口
A chip.
-是纹身  我要去纹身  -纹身
- A tattoo. I'm getting a tattoo. - A tattoo?
你为什么要纹身
Why? Why would you wanna do that?
你不觉得那酷吗
You don't think they're kind of cool?
不  抱歉  我不觉得
No. Sorry, I don't.
怎么会有人花钱去搞个一辈子的伤痕
Why would anyone pay someone to scar their body for life?
万一纹得不理想呢  菲比
What if it doesn't come out right Phoebe?
那不就像永远都在"我头发剪坏了"的状态吗
Then it's like, I don't know, havin' a bad hair cut all the time.
都看我干什么
Why is everyone staring at me?
罗斯  在爸爸的生日贺卡上签个名  理查德随时会到
Ross, come sign this birthday card for dad. Rich is gonna be here any minute.
理查德也要去参加派对
Richard's going to the party too?
他是我父母最好的朋友  他必须去
Well, he's my parents' best friend, he has to be there.
那你打算今天交代你们的关系吗
So is today the day you'll tell them about you two?
对  我爸的生日  我决定送他中风
Yeah, for my dad's birthday, I decided to give him a stroke.
不  你应该告诉他们
No, I think you should tell them.
我还不知道他对我有多认真
No, I don't even know how serious he is about me.
在搞清楚之前  我什么也不说
Until I do, I'm not telling them anything.
也未必吧  我想他们不会介意
I don't know, I don't think mom and dad would mind.
记得你九岁  理查德三十岁时  爸常说
Remember when you were 9 and Richard was 30, how dad used to say
"天啊  真希望他们在一起"
... "God, I hope they get together."
-好了  进去吧   -好  等等  等等
- Alright, shall we, - okay, wait, wait.
不如这样吧
No. You know what?
罗斯  我们换位置  你来站中间
Ross, let's switch places. You get in the middle.
不  这看起来像我们想隐瞒什么
No un-, ya know, unless this looks like we're trying to cover something up.
摩妮卡  就算你骑着他进去
Monica, Monica, you could come in straddling him,
他们也不会相信的
they still wouldn't believe it.
我们来了
We're here!
孩子们  亲爱的
Oh hi kids. Hi darling.
-生日快乐  爸爸  -谢谢
- Happy birthday, Dad. - Thank you.
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
你们谢过伯克医生载你们来了吗
So you kids thanked Dr. Burke for the ride?
妈  事实上  摩妮卡帮我们两个谢过了
Actually, Mom, I think Monica thanked him for the both of us.
你们搭火车来的吗
So you kids take the train in?
不  理查德·伯克载他们来的
No, Richard Burke gave them a ride.
谈到他
Speaking of whom...
听说他在城里交了个二十来岁的笨丫头
... I hear he's got some 20-year-old twinkie in the city.
手指抽筋  天呐
Finger cramp! Oh, God!
抱歉  来  我来擦  妈
Sorry. Here, let me get that, Mom.
理查德在青少年部"购物"
So Richard's shopping in the junior section?
有完没完啊
Are we still on that?
想也知道她一定没什么头脑
You just know she's got the IQ of a napkin.
说不定连漂亮都谈不上
She's probably not even pretty.
只是够年轻  所以一切都还没下垂
Just young enough so that everything is still pointing up.
这地方简直绝了
Can you believe this place?
我知道  这个公寓很棒
I know. This is a great apartment.
我刚去过洗手间  两边墙上都有镜子
Ah, I was just in the bathroom, and there's mirrors on both sides of you.
在里面感觉像是一排人在同时尿尿
So when you're in there it's like you're peein' with the Rockettes.
我的梦想实现了
Well, there's my fantasy come true.
不  说真的
No, seriously.
我们正在夸你的公寓  老兄
We were just saying, great apartment man.
谢了  你要吗
Thanks. You want it?
我要搬去一个更大的
I'm moving to a bigger place.
你真的应该租下来
You should definitely take this one.
你看我会住这种地方吗
Yeah, can you see me in a place like this?
为什么不会  你讨厌公园景观跟高天花板吗
Why not? You hate park views and high ceilings?
来吧  我带你去看厨房
Come on, I'll show you the kitchen.
不用了  兄弟  我今早看到过厨房了
That's all right, fellas, I saw a kitchen this morning.
就在电视上
On TV.
别说了  好
Stop talking. Okay!
-别卖关子了  快说吧  对  -她真只有20岁吗
- Come on, tell us! - ls she really 20?
你们休想逼我说什么
I am not telling you guys anything.
说吧  理查德  今天是我生日  让我过一下干瘾
C'mon Rich, it's my birthday, let me live vicariously.
爸  你会后悔的
Dad, you really don't want to do that.
跟朋友分享一下你的中年危机嘛
What's a little midlife crisis between friends?
杰克  能放我一马吗
Jack, would you let it go?
我了解你的感受  我50岁时买了辆保时捷
Look, I know what you're going through. When I turned 50 I got the Porsche.
你有自己的小"加速器"
You... you got your own little speedster.
-各位  说真的  不是那么回事  -这样吧
- Guys. Seriously, it is not like that. - Tell you what.
或许找个周末  我车子借你  你的小...
Maybe one of these weekends you can borrow the car and I could
爸  我求你别说下去了
Dad, I beg you not to finish that sentence!
怎么  我在逗他
What? I'm kidding!
我才不会让他碰我的保时捷
You know I'd never let him touch the Porsche.
瑞秋
Okay, Rach.
选哪一朵百合  这一朵还是那一朵
Which lily? This lily or that lily?
我喜欢这朵
I - I like this lily.
开得比较大  就像我妈
It's more open and that's like my mom.
她有比较开放和乐于付出的精神
She had a more open, giving spirit.
来亨鸡福亨
Foghorn Leghorn!
金发的  你去二号房间
Blonde girl? You're in room two.
头发没那么黄的  你跟我来
Not-so-blonde girl, you're with me.
走吧
Here we go!
你怎么不走
You're not going.
怎么了  是因为罗斯的话吗
Is this because of what Ross said?
-不是  或许吧  -我真不敢相信
- No. Well, yeah, maybe. - I don't believe this.
你们的关系这样维持吗  罗斯说了算
Is this how this relationship works? Ross equals boss?
少来了  现在是1922年吗
Come on, what is this, 1922?
1922年有什么
What's 1922?
只是很久以前嘛
Just, you know, a long time ago.
当时是女人很多事得听男人的时代
When men used to tell women what to do a lot.
然后还有选举权  那是件好事  但听起来很可怕
Then there was suffrage, which was a good thing. But it sounds horrible.
你到底要不要纹
Do you want to get this tattoo?
我要啊  只是罗斯他...
Yes, I do. It's just that Ross...
你男友是你的老板吗
OK, hey, Hey Is your boyfriend the boss of you?
不是
No.
那好  谁是你的老板
OK, who is the boss of you?!
你
You?
不  你是你自己的老板
No. You are the boss of you!
乖乖给我进去  把那颗红心刺上去
Now you march your heinie in there and get that heart tattooed on your hip.
快去
Go!
你怎么样
How you doing?
我是个笨丫头
I'm a twinkie!
真的  我是英雄
Really? I'm a hero.
真辛苦
This is so hard.
是  我知道  我也讨厌这样
Yeah, I know. I hate it too.
听着  或许我们应该说出来
Look, maybe we should just tell them.
或许我们应该先告诉你父母
Maybe we should just tell your parents first.
我父母死了
My parents are dead.
你真幸运
God, you are so lucky!
不  我是说  你懂我意思
I mean, I mean. . . you know what I mean.
我懂  我懂  再忍耐一下  好吗
I know, I know. Just hang in there, OK?
-好了  我先出去  好吗  -好
- Okay, I'll go out first, all right? - Alright.
朱迪  上洗手间呀  真不错
Judy! Going to the bathroom. Good for you!
谢谢  理查德  很感激你的支持
Thank you, Richard. I appreciate the support.
亲爱的
Honey.
看到我的哈蒙·齐勒布鲁球棒吗  鲍勃不信我有
Honey, have you seen my Harmon Kilerbrew bat? Bob doesn't believe I have one.
完全不知道
I have no idea.
你知道理查德在城里和一个笨丫头交往吗
Did you know Richard has a twinkie in the city?
我知道  他像变了个人一样
I know. He's like a new man.
好像进了"魔茧"一样
It's like a scene from Cocoon.
我怎么也无法想象理查德和淫娃在一起
I just never would have pictured Richard with a bimbo.
他告诉沙约翰·夏皮罗  那个女孩不错
Apparently, he told Johnny Shapiro that she's quite a girl.
事实上  他告诉强尼  他觉得自己爱上她了
In fact, he told Johnny that he thinks he's falling in love with her.
-真的  -告诉你  我没见他这么快乐过
- Really? - I tell you, I've never seen him this happy.
杰克
So, Jack...
你有没有想过  拿我去换个年轻小妞儿
...you ever think about trading me in for a younger model?
当然没有
Of course not.
你不就等于两个二五佳人
With you, it's like I've got two 25-year-olds.
杰克  住手
Oh, Jack, stop!
来嘛
Come on!
今天可是我生日
It's my birthday!
别说了  好吗
Can we drop this?
我对那家伙的公寓没兴趣
I am not interested in the guy's apartment.
别装了  我看到你看他房子装饰的样子
Oh, please. I saw the way you were checking out his moldings.
你想要
You want it.
我为什么要另一间公寓
Why would I want another apartment?
我已经有个我爱的公寓了
I've already got an apartment that I love.
偶尔这样说说又不会死
It wouldn't kill you to say it once in a while.
好吧  想听实话吗  我的确在考虑
All right. You want the truth? I'm thinking about it.
-什么  -抱歉
- What? - I'm sorry.
我今年28了  从没自己住过
I'm 28 years old, I've never lived alone,
而我终于赚到足够的钱
and I'm finally at a place where I've got enough money
可以让我不再需要室友
that I don't need a roommate anymore.
我也不需要室友
I don't need a roommate either.
自己住这里我也负担得起
I can afford to live here by myself.
我或许一个礼拜得请一次人来舔我的餐具
I may have to bring in somebody once a week to lick the silverware.
你火气怎么那么大
What're you gettin' so bent out of shape for, huh?
我们又没说要永远住在一起
It's not like we agreed to live together forever.
我们又不是连体婴
We're not Bert and Ernie.
知道吗
Look, you know what?
如果你这样觉得
If this is the way you feel...
那或许你应该搬去
...then maybe you should take it.
-我是那样觉得  -那或许你应该搬去
- That's how I feel. - Then maybe you should take it!
那或许我会
Maybe I will!
-我没意见  -很好
- Fine with me! - Great!
你就有多点时间跟你真正的朋友在一起
Then you'll be able to spend more quality time with your real friends,
你的汤匙
...the spoons!
谁还要加点饮料
Whose drink can I freshen?
快要切蛋糕了
Almost time for cake!
摩妮卡  你还好吗
Mon, are you okay?
-记得我发现爸妈的那卷录影带吗  -记得
- You remember that video I found of Mom and Dad? - Yeah.
我刚看了现场秀
Well, I just caught the live show.
-嗨  -怎样
- Hey, there. - What?
没什么  我刚听到你的好话
Nothing. I just heard something nice about you.
真的
Really?
理查德  理查德
Richard. Richard.
-你儿子现在没女友吧  -据我所知  没有
- Your son isn't seeing anyone is he? - Not that I know of.
我是在想  他何不打个电话给摩妮卡
I was thinking, why doesn't he give Monica a call?
这主意不错
That's an idea.
事实上  我已经有男友了
Well, actually, I'm already seeing someone.
这孩子什么事都不讲
She never tells us anything.
罗斯  你知道摩妮卡有男友了吗
Ross, did you know Monica's seeing someone?
妈  我周遭有好多人
Mom, there are so many people in my life.
有些人有男友  有些人没有
Some of them are seeing people and some of them aren't.
够清楚吗
Is that crystal?
那个神秘男子是谁
So who's the mystery man?
他是个医生
Well, he's a doctor.
真正的医生
A real doctor?
不  他是兽医
No, a doctor of meat.
他当然是真的医生
Of course he's a real doctor.
还很英俊
And he's handsome.
也很体贴  我知道你会喜欢他
And he's sweet, and I know you'd like him.
那太棒了
Well, that's wonderful.
妈  没关系
Mom, it's okay.
没错  朱迪
It is, Judy.
杰克
Jack!
你能过来一下吗
Could you come in here for a moment?
就现在
Now!
-找到了  -交给我  爸
- Found it! - I'll take that, Dad.
你女儿跟理查德看来似乎是一对
It seems your daughter and Richard are something of an item.
那不可能  他在城里有个笨丫头
That's impossible. He's got a twinkie in the city.
爸  我就是那个笨丫头
Dad, I'm the twinkie.
-你就是那个笨丫头  -她不是个笨丫头
- You're the twinkie? - She's not a twinkie!
好吧  听着  各位  这是我最棒的一段感情
Alright,look you guys, this is the best relationship I've been in. . .
拜托  感情
Oh, please! A relationship?
对  感情
Yes, a relationship!
你们请听好  我爱死这个男人了
For your information, I'm crazy about this man.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yes.
我生日还要站在这里  听你说这些鬼话吗
Am I supposed to stand here and listen to this on my birthday?
爸  这对我而言是件好事
Dad, dad this is a good thing for me.
你自己也说  你没见理查德那么快乐过
Ya know, and you even said yourself, you've never seen Richard happier.
我什么时候说的
When did I say that?
楼上洗手间  就在你摸妈之前
Upstairs in the bathroom, right before you felt up Mom!
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快乐  杰克
Happy birthday, dear Jack
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
太漂亮了  我好喜欢
It looks so good! Oh, I love it.
我知道  我也是  菲比  我好高兴你逼我纹身
I know, so do I. Oh Phoebe, I'm so glad you made me do this.
让我看你的
Okay, let me see yours.
再瞧瞧你的
OK, let's see yours again.
菲比  我的才刚看过  让我看你的
Phoebe we just saw mine, let me see yours.
好吧
Oh, OK.
不
Oh, no!
不见了  太诡异了
It's gone! That's so weird.
不知道去哪里了
I don't know how, where it went.
-你没纹身  -没
- You didn't get it? - No.
你为什么没
Why didn't you get it?
对不起
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
菲比  你怎么可以这样对我  这全是你的主意
Phoebe, how would you do this to me? This was all your idea
我知道  我本来是要纹的  可是他拿着针走进来
I know! I was gonna get it, but he came in with this needle.
你知道他们是用针纹的吗
And did you know they do this with needles?
真的吗  你怎么不早说
Really? You don't say?
因为我的是猫舔上去的
Because mine was licked on by kittens!
听着  今天的事我很抱歉
Hey listen, I'm sorry about what happened. . .
-我也是  -我知道
- Yeah, me too. - I know.
我们需要抱一下吗
So do we need to hug here or. . .?
不  没关系
No, we're all right.
我有东西送你
So I got you something.
塑料汤匙
Plastic spoons!
-太棒了  -舔吧  老兄
- Great! - Lick away, my man!
能先在我新家用上  过渡一下
These will go great in my new place till I get real ones.
什么
What?
我不能永远用塑料汤匙  这不环保
I can't use these forever. Let's face it, they're no friend to the environment.
不  我是说   你说什么新家
No, I mean what's this about your new place?
我要搬出去  我们谈过的
I'm moving out, like we talked about.
我不知道你是认真的
I didn't think that was serious.
我以为我们只是在吵架
You know, I thought that was just a fight.
我们是吵架了
Well, it was a fight...
有根有据的  记得吗
... based on serious stuff, remember?
关于我从没一个人住过
About how I never lived alone or anything?
我只是想  这对我有好处  帮我成长
I think it would be good for me. Help me to grow...
之类的
...or whatever.
那好吧
Well, there you go.
你不会生气吧
Hey, are you cool with this?
我不想让你孤单寂寞
I don't wanna leave you high and dry.
我可从不觉得有多热闹
I've never been lower or wetter.
我不要紧的  我准备把你的房间
I'll be fine. I'll just turn your...
改成游戏室之类的
... bedroom into a game room or somethin', you know,
把足球桌放在里面
Put the foosball table in there.
为什么桌子归你
Why do you get to keep the table?
我付了一半的钱
I did pay for half of it.
对  我付了另一半
Yeah. And uh, I paid for the other half.
这样吧  谁赢归谁
I'll tell you what. I'll play you for it.
好  没问题
All right, you're on.
我可以抽两分钟杀你个片甲不留
I can take two minutes out of my day to kick your ass.
我得的分会比你妹被上过的次数还多
Your little men are gonna get scored on more times than your sister.
哪个妹妹
Which sister?
你后悔我告诉他们吗
So are you sorry that I told them?
不  我跟你爸好久没去跑步了
No. It's been a long time since your dad and I went running.
你们纹身了吗  给我看
Well did you get it? Let me see.
-罗斯在吗  -不在  他买披萨去了
- ls Ross here? - No he went out to get pizza.
抓紧
Oh really quick, O.K.
好漂亮
That's great!
很有味道
Very tasteful.
-要看我的吗  -要
- Wanna see mine? Wanna see mine? - Yes.
什么  你又没纹
What? You didn't get one.
那这是什么
Okay. Well then, what is this?
要我们看什么
What are we looking at?
那块蓝雀斑
That blue freckle?
那是我的纹身
That's my tattoo.
那不是纹身  什么也不是
That is not a tattoo. That is a nothing.
我好不容易让她回去纹身
I finally got her back in the chair,
针根本都还没碰到她  她就叫唤着跑了
...he barely touched her with the needle, she screamed and that was it.
好吧
Okay, hi!
说实在的  这正是我想要的纹身
For your information, this is exactly what I wanted.
这是个从很遥远的地方看到的地球
This is a tattoo of the Earth as seen from a great, great distance.
我妈从天堂看到我就是这样的
It's the way my mother sees me from heaven.
放屁
Oh, what a load of crap!
那只是一个点
That is a dot!
你妈正在天堂上大叫"我的百合在哪里  孬种"
Your mother's in heaven going, "Where the hell's my lily, you wuss!"
菲比  那不是个纹身  这才是个纹身
OK, Phoebe, that is not a tattoo. This is a tattoo!
你去纹身了
You got a tattoo?
大概吧
Maybe.
我只纹了个小的  菲比纹了全世界
But just a little one. Phoebe got the whole world!
让我看看
Well, let me see.
怎样
Well?
还真是...
Well, it's really...
性感
...sexy.
我没想到会这样  但...
I wouldn't have thought it would be, but...
真的
Really?
对  所以会酸痛吗  你可以活动吗
Yeah, so uh, is it sore or can you do stuff?
可以吧
I guess.
留些匹萨给我们
Save us some pizza.
别窝在角落
Get it out of the corner!
传球  传球
Pass it! Pass it!
别跟你的小兵讲话
Stop talking to your men!
帅  桌子是我的了
Yes! And the table is mine.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
你们还是会来看我  对吧
You guys will still come visit me, right?
当然  你有大屏幕电视
Oh, yeah! You got the big TV.
我们会常去做客
We'll be over there all the time.
要不就是来这里
Except when we are here.
我知道你只是往北搬  我还是会想你的
I know you're just moving uptown, but I'll really miss you.
你怎么就不做我的对门了
I know, how can you not be accross the hall anymore.
是啊  谁来吃光我们的东西  占用我们的电话
Yeah, who's gonna eat all our food, and tie up our phone lines, and...
那是我的胸罩吗
Is that my bra?
你拿我的胸罩去干什么
What are you doing with my bra?
不  你想歪了
Oh no-no, it's uh, it's not what you think.
我们用来在屋顶上弹水球
We used it to fling water balloons off the roof.
记得吗  那些初中生连弹到对面都办不到
Remember that, those junior high kids couldn't even get theirs accross the street.
是啊  我记得
Yeah, I remember.
咱们把剩下的搬上卡车
Let's bring the rest of these down to the truck.
那...你要我
So, uhh, em, you want me to uh,
帮你搬这个足球桌下去吗
...give you a hand with the foosball table?
不了  你留着  你需要练习
Naa, you keep it, you need the practice.
谢了
Thanks.
所以...
So...
那就这样了
... I guess this is it.
是啊  对
Yeah, right, yeah.
应该是
I guess so.
我不知道我们什么时候会再见
Listen, uh, I don't know when I'm gonna see you again.
今晚在咖啡馆吧
I'm guessing tonight at the coffeehouse.
对啊
Right. Yeah. Okay.
保重了
Take care.